

https://guillermo.onrender.com 555-158-8911 & guillermo.uriel.cruz.fuente@gmail.com ☑ Texcoco, State of Mexico (9)

Detail-oriented developer with more than 3 years of experience implementing enterprise solutions. Always trying to apply the best practices, using modern tools that optimize my workflow and help me develop beautiful and functional websites.

EXPERIENCE

harBest

https://harbest.mx

Frontend Developer & UX/UI Designer [2019-2022]

Design a proposal that enhances the main characteristics of the brand. A fast and minimalistic website with the most basic tech stack: HTML5, SCSS, and JavaScript. It has suffered a lot of changes throughout time, thanks to the CEO's feedback and a continuous catalog expansion. Due to this, client conversion reached its highest point in 4 years.

Intelligentia

https://intelligentia.onrender.com

Frontend Developer & UX/UI Designer [2020-2022]

Landing page design and development. The key action to obtain the first significant number of clients. Various responsibilities include audiovisual editor, brand logo animator, and Android developer. Creation of an app that helps the team to do surveys in difficult-access communities. Optimizing the data gathering by centralizing the process to subsequently analyze it.

CampoFuerte

https://campofuerte.onrender.com

Frontend Developer & UX/UI Designer [2021-2022]

Assist this Enterprise by creating a completely brand-new website. The previous one was made with WordPress; slow loading speed and a boring template were the main problems to solve. More than 200% improvement in its loading time by just using HTML5, SCSS, and TypeScript. Also, all grammatical and spelling errors were removed, contributing even more to its professionalism and reliability.

SKILLS

Development











- Experience with CSS3, SCSS, HTML5, JavaScript, TypeScript, and ReactJS (TSX) with functional components.
- Responsive design, flex and grid layouts, CSS animations with keyframes and transition properties, advanced selectors, CSS-in-JS libraries like Emotion, etc.
- Vite as main bundler.
- npm dependencies.
- Rest API requests handling.
- Git and GitHub workflow.

UX/UI Design









- UI design with Adobe XD and Figma
- Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to edit, improve and export assets.
- Logo animation in Adobe After Effects and Lottie JSON export.
- Video editing with Premiere Pro and After Effects.

Languages

• English - Level B2

• Spanish - Native

EDUCATION

Autonomous University Chapingo [2014 - 2020] Mechatronics Engineering (not concluded)

Desertion was caused by economic problems, mainly. Although, some achievements are worth mentioning, such as:

- MetQ, desktop application to calculate the potential evapotranspiration in open field crops and soil granulometry, developed in C#.
- MatLab GUI to simulate and calculate forces in static structures.